（牧瀬紅莉栖(まきせくりす)）うん？
（岡部倫太郎(おかべりんたろう)）あ… ああっ
（橋田 至(はしだいたる)）ちょっ オカリン？
Okarin?
なぜ？
How?
なぜだ？ あっ！
（紅莉栖）あっ… ああっ！
（紅莉栖）ええっ？
（岡部）ある！
I can feel her. She's really here.
実態がある
はあ？ ああっ
You're not a ghost?
幽霊ではないのか？
Do you want me to call the cops?
おのれは警察に突き出されたいか？
I just want to know the truth!
俺は真実を知りたいだけだ
You were stabbed here...
刺されたのは確か…
（紅莉栖）ああっ！
あっ あっ…
（橋田）おお
（紅莉栖）何が真実よ！
What do you mean by "the truth"?
Are you stupid? Do you want to die?
バカなの？ 死ぬの？
That's Louise's famous line!
ルイスちゃんの名ぜりふ
キタコレ！
I saw it!
（岡部）俺は確かに見たのだ！
You were stabbed!
お前が刺されているのを！
えっ？
Three hours ago,
（岡部）３時間ほど前 ラジ館の
中鉢(なかばち)博士 記者会見のとき…
during Professor Nakabachi's press conference at the radio—
Okarin, try to control your delusions.
（橋田）オカリン
妄想はチラ裏だけにしとけって
Professor Nakabachi's press conference was called off!
中鉢博士の会見は
中止になったっしょ！
But...
しかし！
Ms. Makise! It's almost time!
（係員）牧瀬さん！
そろそろ お時間です
（紅莉栖）あっ はい
Yes!
Wait! Are you running away?
（岡部）あっ 待て！ 逃げるのか？
（橋田）ああ…
You're...
あなたは？
I have a name.
（岡部）あなたではない
It's Hououin...
鳳凰院(ほうおういん)…
Kyouma!
凶真(きょうま)だ！
Time Travel
Paranoia
～
Are Time Machines Possible?
Thank you all for coming here today.
（紅莉栖）
本日は お集まりいただきまして
ありがとうございます
えー このような講演は
なかなか経験がないため―
I don't have much experience with lectures like these,
不慣れな点もあるかと思いますが
よろしくお願いします
so I hope you'll bear with me.
（拍手）
（橋田）
講師 牧瀬紅莉栖だったんだ
Makise Kurisu's giving the lecture...
So, she isn't a ghost?
やはり幽霊ではないのか
まだ言っとるん？
Still bringing that up?
I've been asked to speak to you about time machines.
（紅莉栖）
今回 タイムマシンをテーマに
話してほしいと言われました
It's a different theme from what I presented in my Science Magazine essay,
「サイエンシー」に
載せていただいた―
論文のテーマとは異なりますが
頑張って話してみようと思います
but I'd like to give it a try.
Time machines?
タイムマシン？
I have come to the conclusion that...
（紅莉栖）
私の結論から言ってしまうと…
フッ
...time machines are foolish stuff.
タイムマシンなんていうのは
バカらしい代物だということです
I'd like to spend the lecture discussing how I arrived at that conclusio—
なぜ そう結論づけられるか―
これから考察しながら…
（岡部）異義あり！
（紅莉栖）えっ？
Objection!
Huh?
（ざわめき）
（岡部）タイムマシンが作れない？
Time machines are impossible?
フッ…
決めつけは早計だ！
It's far too early to decide that!
オカリン 無茶しやがって
Okarin, you're embarrassing yourself.
あなたは？
You're...
（紅莉栖）あっ
（係員）あっ うん…
早計というより―
Rather than being early,
理論上 否定されるべきものでは
ないかというのが―
I believe that it's just theoretically impossible.
私の見解なのですが
なんだと？
What?
うんっ
Well then, let's change the format of this lecture to a discussion.
（紅莉栖）
では ディスカッション形式に
しましょうか
That will make it easier for certain stubborn people to understand.
そのほうが頭の固いお方にも
ご理解いただけそうですし
ねえ？ 鳳凰院凶真さん
Right? Mr. Hououin Kyouma?
（岡部）フッ
（岡部）ああ… ああ…
Makise Kurisu...
牧瀬紅莉栖…
From this we can conclude that,
（紅莉栖）以上において―
in a universe based on string theory, time travel is unrealistic.
宇宙ひも理論における
タイムトラベルは―
現実的ではありませんが
挑戦してみます？
Do you want to try it?
Mr. Hououin?
鳳凰院さん
（岡部）くくく…
そうですね…
That's right...
Then why not find some exotic matter for us,
じゃあ エキゾチック物質
見つけてくださいよ
Mr. Hououin?
鳳凰院さん
くうう…
That's all I have to say.
以上で私の話は終わりですが
それでも反論があるなら聞きますよ
But if you have any further objections, I'm listening.
Mr. Hououin!
鳳凰院さん
だああっ　ちょっと天才だからと
いい気になりおってー！
Don't be so damned arrogant, just because you're little bit of genius!
あっ 待てよ　あの小娘
恐らくは機関のエージェント
Wait... She must be an agent of the Organization!
It's hot... It's so hot...
The lecture was, in itself,
この講義そのものが―
an act of carefully planned psychological warfare, aimed at me!
周到に仕組まれた
俺への精神攻撃だと…
フッ その手には乗らぬわ
Well, I'm not falling for it.
（岡部）あっ？
（岡部）んっ？
（漆原(うるしばら)るかの荒い息）
Yanagibayashi
Shrine
Eight...
（るか）８…
（るかの荒い息）
（椎名(しいな)まゆり）９　あと１回
Nine...
Just one more swing.
You can do it!
せーの
（るか）ハア… 10！
（まゆり）10！
Ten!
Way to go, Ruka!
（まゆり）るか君 すごい
あっ オカリン　トゥットゥルー
Ah, Okarin!
えっ？ あっ 岡部さ…
Mr. O-Okabe... No, Mr. Kyouma.
あっ いえ 凶真… さん
合い言葉を忘れているぞ るか子よ
You forgot the secret words, Rukako.
（るか）えっ？
あっ えっ…
エルプサイ コ コンガリィ
E-El Psy... Congre...
Congroo!
（岡部）コングルゥだ
I-I'm sorry.
（るか）すっ すみません
それで？ 荷物というのは？
So, what did you want me to carry?
This right here.
ここだよ　ごめんね
Sorry.
Mayushii can't carry all this.
まゆしぃ１人では
持てそうになかったのです
父がもらってきて
My dad brought them, and we can't eat them all.
うちでは食べきれないので
I see.
そうか
Thank you for donating these provisions to the lab.
ラボへの食料提供 感謝する
This will raise morale amongst the lab members.
ラボメンの士気も上がることだろう
（るか）よかったです
（岡部）んっ？
I'm so glad you like them!
喜んでもらえて
Um... Well...
（岡部）あっ いや その…
（まゆり）るか君
毎日 素振り続けてるんだよね
Ruka practices swinging a sword daily!
Yes. I promised Oka... I mean, Mr. Kyouma.
はい　岡… あっ
凶真さんとの約束なので
（岡部）うむ
When the Magical Blade Samidare acknowledges you as a suitable wielder,
妖刀五月雨(さみだれ)は―
るか子が ふさわしい使い手と
感知したときに―
真の力を発揮する
it will show its true power.
Do not forget that.
（岡部）忘れるなよ
（るか）はい
Yes!
You got such a deal on it at the weapons store. Only 980 yen!
そんな剣が「武器屋本舗」で
980円なんて お買い得だったね
では 鍛錬の成果を見せてもらおう
Then, show me the results of your training.
Can you attempt an exorcism?
おはらいは できるか？
（るか）えっ？ 一応は…
I-I suppose... But...
でも ちゃんとした おはらいなら
お父さんのほうが…
If you need a real exorcism, you should talk to my father—
（るか）あっ！
（岡部）あああっ！ わっ…
我が右腕に取りついた悪霊が！
An evil spirit has possessed my right hand!
Hurry and perform the exorcism, before the power overtakes my entire body!
早く おはらいを！
あの力が全身を犯す前に…
（るか）はい！
R-Right!
That's a different hand than from last time.
（まゆり）この前と手が逆だよ
（岡部）うう… 今日は
悪霊が こっちに取りついたのだ
The evil spirit possessed this one today, okay?
Urushibara Ruka.
（岡部）漆原るか
The mannerisms and voice of a woman...
声もしぐさも
女にしか見えない
No... More feminine than any woman.
いや　女より女らしい美少女
But he's a guy.
だが 男だ
Taller than Mayuri, but so very thin...
まゆりより背は高いが
体つきは とても細い
だが 男だ
But he's a guy.
巫女(みこ)服が似合っている
Looks great in a shrine maiden outfit...
But he's a guy.
だが 男だ
It's already twilight.
もう夕暮れだというのに暑いな
And yet, it's so hot.
セミが鳴いている
The cicadas are crying.
だが…
But...
ウフッ
He's a guy.
（岡部）男だ
Bye-bye!
バイバーイ
Ruka's so great, able to do those exorcisms!
（まゆり）るか君
おはらいできるなんて すごいね
Because he's the scion of a shrine clan.
神社の息子だからな
ウフッ　バサーッ バサーッて…
（まゆり）あああっ あっ…
（岡部）おおおっ
Sorry.
（まゆり）ごめん
（岡部）うん
Akihabara
Police
Restricted
Area
（まゆり）あー
It's off-limits?
通行止めか？
（まゆり）
ここ通るとラジ館の裏だからね
Yeah, this leads behind the radio building.
ラジ館
The radio building...
（岡部）あっ
（まゆり）うーん
（岡部）それも こっちによこせ
Give me those.
えっ？
（岡部）バイトの時間だろ？ ほれ
You've got part-time work soon, don't you?
Come on.
（まゆり）うーん　ありがとう
Thank you.
I'm working late tonight, so I'm going straight home afterwards.
今日はシフト遅いから―
終わったら
そのまま帰っちゃうと思う
（岡部）まゆり
（まゆり）んっ？
Mayuri!
You really didn't hear a scream, did you?
お前 本当に
悲鳴は聞いていないんだな？
（まゆり）悲鳴？ いつ？
A scream? When?
Today, at the radio building.
今日 ラジ館でだ
うーん… 聞いてないかな
I don't think I did.
そうか
I see...
分かった　だったらいい
All right.
Then that's fine.
（まゆり）えー？ 変なオカリン
You're weird, Okarin.
So, no one remembers...
（岡部）やはり
誰１人として覚えてはいない
まゆりもダルも牧瀬紅莉栖も
Not Mayuri. Not Daru. Not Makise Kurisu.
（天王寺裕吾(てんのうじゆうご)）うん…
Open
Closed
You're closing up early today, Mr. Braun!
（岡部）今日は早いのだな
（天王寺）うーん…
（岡部）ミスターブラウン
（天王寺）だから その呼び方
やめろっつってんだろ
I told you not to call me that.
I'm interviewing a part-timer today.
今日はバイトの面接があってな
バイト？
A part-timer?
フッ この辛気くさくて
客もおらず―
At a dreary shop with no customers,
run by an over-muscled old man?
むさいおっさんが店長の
この店に？ ハハハ…
You know...
おめえな…
（阿万音鈴羽(あまねすずは)）えいっ
（天王寺）なっ…
（鈴羽）おっはー
'Sup!
（岡部）はっ？
（天王寺）ハアー
あれ？ はやりの挨拶って
聞いたんだけど
Huh? I heard that's the popular way to say "hi" now.
This can't possibly be your part-timer...
まさか バイトというのは？
Is it a problem?
悪いか
（天王寺）名前は？
（鈴羽）阿万音鈴羽
Your name?
Amane Suzuha.
Age?
（天王寺）年は？
（鈴羽）18
Eighteen.
Reason for working here?
（天王寺）志望動機は？
（鈴羽）ブラウン管が好きだから
I love CRT TVs!
（天王寺）採用
（鈴羽）…っしゃあ！
You're hired!
Is this a comedy routine?
待て　これはコントか？
しこみか？
Some kind of joke?
Who are you?
そういう君は？
His name's Okabe.
（天王寺）岡部ってんだ
この上に間借りしてるバカだよ
He's an idiot who rents a room upstairs.
It's not Okabe! It's Hououin—
岡部ではない　鳳凰院…
（天王寺）
うっせい！ 家賃 倍にすんぞ！
Shut up! I'll double your rent.
（岡部）岡部倫太郎だ
（鈴羽）よろしく
I'm Okabe Rintarou.
Hi!
Say, what's in those bags?
（鈴羽）ねえ その袋は何？
Special Intelligence Corn that was donated to the lab.
あっ ラボに提供された
インテリジェンス･コーンだ
欲しくば それ相応の対価を…
If you want some, you must adequately compensate—
Corn?
コーンって小さいツブツブの？
With the little bumps?
So this is how it originally looks.
へえー 元は こんななんだ
（岡部）知らんのか？
（鈴羽）見ても…
You didn't know?
Can I see—?
（岡部）おっと
（鈴羽）あっ…
Hold it.
The Organization has targeted many people
多くの人が俺と知り合ったことで
機関に狙われた
because they've come into contact with me.
Sara, Claudia, Simona...
サラ　クラウディア　シモーヌ
そうなんだ
よかったら相談に乗るよ
I see.
If you want, we could talk about it.
Don't worry about him. He's just making that up.
本気にすんな　こいつの創作だよ
えっ？
フフッ
せいぜい そう思い込むがいい
Think what you'd like.
Someday, the entire world will bow at my feet.
いずれ この世界は
俺に ひざまずくことになる
So, that's what's popular these days—
（鈴羽）へえー
ああいうのがはやって… あっ
ふーん
Unknown satellite crashes near Akihabara Station, around 12:00...
Crashed, around 12:00...
（岡部）
12時ごろ… 落下
まゆりたちの言うことに間違いない
Mayuri and Daru were right.
ハッ
会見は中止？
Professor Nakabachi's Press Conference Cancelled
The conference was canceled?
“牧瀬紅莉栖”“事件”
Makise Kurisu incident...
Was that some kind of hallucination?
俺が見たものは幻だったのか？
channel
うん？ ジョン･タイター？
John Titor?
A time traveler's here! lololol
SERN maintains an exclusive monopoly on time machines.
（ジョン･タイター）
“タイムマシンは”
“ＳＥＲＮ(セルン)によって
独占されています”
Neither civilians nor corporations may acquire one.
“一般人も企業も
手に入れることは できません”
They've used the time machine for their sole benefit,
“彼らは自身の利益のためだけに
用いて―”
to bring about dystopia.
“世界にディストピアを
もたらしました”
I've come here to change the future.
“私は未来を変えるために
やってきました”
“ＳＥＲＮによって作られた
ディストピアを破壊し”
To destroy SERN's dystopia, and to set the world free again.
“再び自由を手にするためです”
Then you claim that SERN are dictators?
（栗悟飯(くりごはん)とカメハメ波(は)）
“つまり ＳＥＲＮ イコール
独裁者って言いたいのか？”
（タイター）“いわゆる
祖父のパラドックスですね”
You mean the so-called Grandfather Paradox, right?
257 Name: Nameless Prophet-san [sage]
All I can think of is the European Laboratory for Particle Physics.
“それは存在しません”
There's no such thing.
451 Name: Nameless Prophet-san [sage]
If you time travel, can you meet yourself in the past?
It's possible to meet yourself in the past.
“過去の自分に
会うことも可能です”
If you do, you simply move world lines.
“その場合 世界線が移動します”
What's a world line?
Inb4 parallel worlds.
Let me begin by saying
“まず 時間は
過去から未来へと流れる”
that time isn't a single line, moving from past to future.
“１本の線ではありません”
It's comprised of an infinite number of parallel lines,
“世界線という無数に
並行に流れる―”
like rivers, called "world lines."
“川のようなもので
形成されています”
For example, let's say a serial killer was to murder you today.
“例えば あなたが
今日 通り魔に殺されるとします”
“それを未来から来た私が
防いだとすれば”
If I came from the future and prevented it,
“あなたが殺された世界と
生き延びた世界の２つに―”
the world would diverge into two streams:
a world in which you survived, and a world in which you died.
“世界は分岐するというわけです”
フッ
So, this time's Titor is Japanese, huh?
今度のタイターは日本人か
In the year 2000,
（岡部）2000年ごろ
アメリカのネット上に現れた
a self-proclaimed time-traveler appeared on the American internet.
自称 タイムトラベラー
He claimed he'd come from the year 2036, to save the future.
2036年から未来の世界を救うために
タイムトラベルしてきたという
He then became famous on the internet,
当時はネットで大騒ぎになり
関連書も いくつか出た
leading to several books being published about him.
しかし…
I didn't think I'd see some idiot pretending to be Titor now.
今 ジョン･タイターをかたる
バカがいるとはな…
618 Name: Nameless Prophet-san [sage]
Pretending to be? Huh?
チッ このリンクでも見て
タイターのことぐらい調べてこい
Then click this link and go read up on Titor!
Daru must've deleted the link on Titor...
ダルのやつ
タイターのリンクを消したな
John Titor            About 12 Results
12件？
Twelve?
バカな
Impossible.
10年たったとはいえ―
Sure, it was ten years ago, but it was huge!
あれだけ騒ぎに
なったんだぞ
そんなこと！
It can't be!
John Titor      About 56 results
（岡部）ない… ない！
They're not here!
They're not here! Why?
なぜだ？
関連書は ここに集めていたはず
I had a book collection on him, right here.
クソッ
Damn it!
んっ…
Hello?
もしもし ダル
Daru?
What is it?
（橋田）
何？ 今 フェイリスたんと…
I'm at Feyri—
（岡部）本はどうした？
（橋田）えっ？ 本って？
What happened to the books?
The books?
ジョン･タイターに関する本だ
The books on John Titor.
I had a bunch of them on the bookshelf, didn't I?
本棚に
まとめて置いてあっただろう
どこにある？
Where'd they all go?
（橋田）ちょ… オカリン
（岡部）何だ？
Wait, Okarin?
What?
This John Titor...
（橋田）ジョン･タイターって…
Who is he?
誰ぞ？
I stayed up most of the night looking into John Titor.
（岡部）ほぼ徹夜で 俺は
ジョン･タイターについて調べた
I found every bit of information I could on the internet.
ネットの検索を駆使し
あらゆる情報を集めた
But...
しかし…
I want an answer from Titor.
（岡部）
“タイターに答えてほしい”
“10年前…
つまり2000年のことだ”
About ten years ago... In other words, the year 2000.
It's interesting that you should ask that.
（タイター）
“面白いことを言う人ですね”
“しかし 残念ながら2000年には
行ったことはありません”
But unfortunately, I've never been to the year 2000.
“また その予定もありません”
Nor do I intend to go.
あっ
（岡部）あっ？
（岡部）あっ！
あっ おい！ 待て
Hey! Wait!
You there! You! You! Wait!
ウェイ ウェイ ウェイ
そこの お前！ いや あなた
待て！ あっ 待ってください
Please wait!
You took my picture, didn't you?
今 俺を撮ったな？
すぐ削除したほうが身のためだ
You should delete it! For your own sake!
（桐生萌郁(きりゅうもえか)）あっ
謝る　不快な思いをさせたのなら
I apologize,
if I've made you unhappy.
おお… 何を撮っていたのだ？
What were you taking pictures of?
Proof.
（萌郁）証明
（岡部）えっ？
Of where I walked today.
自分が…
今日…
どこを歩いて…
Of what I saw.
何を見たか
（萌郁）聞きたいことがある
（岡部）えっ？
I want to ask you about something.
This.
（萌郁）これ
ずいぶん古いパソコンだな
That's a really old PC.
Do you recognize it?
（萌郁）知ってる？
（岡部）あっ いや
No.
Do you know anyone who might?
詳しい人は？
あるいはダルなら
Daru, maybe...
Who is that?
その人 誰？
Nothing to do with you.
貴様には関係ない
写真は削除するように
Delete that photo.
（萌郁）うっ
（岡部）うっ なっ…
Tell me...
（萌郁）教えて メアド その人の
The e-mail...
For that person.
断る！
I refuse!
（萌郁）んっ
You... Are you threatening me?
貴様 脅そうというのか？
If you tell me,
（萌郁）教えてくれたら 消す
I'll delete it.
ぬっ… いいだろう
Very well.
ただし 仲間を売るわけにはいかん
But I won't sell out my friends!
I'll give you my own address.
教えるのは俺のメアドだ
What's your name?
名前は？
It says "Hououin Kyouma" right there!
鳳凰院凶真と
書いてあるだろう　あっ
Oubouin Kyouma
ああ…
Give me that.
（岡部）貸せ
（萌郁）うっ
（萌郁の震える息）
（岡部）ああ…
あっ… 空メールを送れ
こっちから送り返す
Send me a blank mail.
I'll just send something back.
Welcome back, Master!
（メイド）
おかえりニャさいませ ご主人様
（まゆり）あー オカリンだ
It's Okarin!
Welcome home, Okarin!
おかえりニャさいませ オカリーン
Yo, Mayuri.
よお まゆり
When I'm working, it's Mayushii Nyan Nyan!
（まゆり）バイト中は
まゆしぃニャンニャンだよ
Come to think of it, "Okarin" kind of sounds like "welcome."
そういえば “オカリン”と
“おかえり”は似てるね
（岡部）あー ダルは？
（まゆり）あっ 奧にいるよ
Where's Daru?
He's in the back.
（フェイリス）あっ 凶真！
Kyouma!
I've missed you.
待ちかねていたニャーぞ
What happened to your promise to visit every three days?
３日に１度は顔を出す約束
どうなったニャ！
I'm sorry.
すまない　機関の妨害がひどく…
The Organization's sabotage has been just awful.
ニャニャ！
そこまで機関は迫ってるニャ？
The Organization's gone that far?
Then you'll hold another secret meeting today on defeating them?
では 今日も機関 打倒のための
極秘会議ニャ？
That's right.
そうだ　いつもの
ステルスフィールドを頼む
Give me the usual Stealth Field.
You're selfish!
合点ニャ
そんで フェイリスも
混ぜてほしいニャ
I want to join—
よせ！
No!
The Organization is far too vast for you to handle!
お前が太刀打ちできるほど
機関は甘くない
フッ このフェイリスには―
But I've got my forbidden special move...
禁断の秘奥義があるニャ
なに？
まさか 会得したというのか？
What?
You finally mastered it?
That's right.
その まさかニャ
After months of harsh training in the Guiana Highlands
ギアナ高地で
修行に耐え抜き―
師匠の死も
乗り越えて―
and overcoming my master's death, at last I...
フェイリスは ついに…
かっ！ 手に入れたのニャー！
I've mastered it!
（橋田）許さない 絶対にだ
I'll never forgive you. Ever.
あっ
それでメールした件だが
So, about what I said in my mail...
I believe talking to a winner makes me a loser.
（橋田）
勝ち組に話したら負けだと思ってる
はあ…
安心しろ　ウソで
塗り固めた女に興味はない
Don't worry.
I've no interest in that girl and her lies.
今日の“お前が言うなスレ”は
ここですか？
Is this today's "you're the last one I want to hear that from" thread?
黙れ！ 浮気野郎が
Shut up, cheater!
Your 2D wives are crying.
２次元の嫁が泣いているぞ
Feyris is special!
フェイリスたんは別！
３次元でも
２次元魂を宿してるお！
She may be 3D, but she has a 2D soul!
それより見てもらいたい
Anyways, look at this.
This picture.
この写真なんだが
おう これＩＢＮ5100っしょ
That's an IBN 5100, right?
IBN?
ＩＢＮ？
A legendary retro-PC.
（橋田）幻のレトロＰＣ
About a month ago I think...
１か月くらい前だったかな
I'd heard a rumor one was somewhere in Akihabara.
秋葉原(あきはばら)のどこかに眠っているという
うわさが流れたから―
She must've heard about it.
それ聞きつけて 来たんじゃね？
（岡部）それで？
（橋田）結局 見つからないまま
What happened?
No one ever found it.
疾風迅雷のナイトハルトまで
出張ってきたけど―
Even the famous "Lightning Speed Night Heart" tried to find it and failed.
Meaning it probably never existed in the first place, is my final answer.
出てこないってことは―
元から なかったんじゃねえか
ってことでファイナルアンサー
（岡部）そんなに貴重な物なのか
Is it that valuable?
発売は今から30年以上前
It was sold over thirty years ago.
At the time, no one bought PCs. They were too expensive.
当時は値段高すぎで
パソコンなんて誰も買えない時代
レア度 激高(げきだか)ってパターン
That's how stuff ends up incredibly rare.
ふむ…
（岡部）おっ？
That girl...
さっきの女か…
I sent that mail...
“早速 メールしました
桐生萌郁です”
I'm Kiryuu Moeka...
Sender: The Lightning Shiatsu-ist
Subject: I'm waiting
Hououin, I sent that mail! I'm Kiryuu Moeka!
Age 20! No real job!
I can mail you, right?
I'm sending it, whether you like it or not!
Moeka
"Age 20..." "No real job..." "I'm sending it, whether you like it or not..."
“ハタチ　フリーター”
“イヤだって言っても
しちゃいま…”
これが さっきの女と
同一人物だというのか？
Is this the same girl I just talked to?
（橋田）どしたん？
What's wrong?
Be glad I didn't sell you out.
お前を売らなかったことに
感謝するんだな
It's a rare and valuable PC,
“貴重なＰＣだ
秋葉(あきば)にはない可能性が高い”
but there's a good chance it's not in Akihabara.
El Psy Congroo.
エル･プサイ･コングルゥ
Master!
ご主人様　お待たせニャンニャン
Here you go, Nyan Nyan!
（橋田）うひょー！
The
World's
in Danger!!
It's "The World's in Danger"!
“世界がヤバい！！” キターッ
Let's eat!
（橋田）いただきまーす
（フェイリス）ウフッ 召し上がれ
Calm down.
落ち着けって　あっ…
The
World's in Dang
er!!
（岡部）大学の研究室で
分析を行った結果―
Analysis by the university laboratory reveals that
ゲルバナは電子レベルで
ズタズタだということが判明した
the gel-banas have been torn apart at a molecular level.
（橋田）ふーん
So they turned into something that wasn't a banana.
バナナではない 何かになってたと
Isn't that bad?
それ ヤバくねえ？
何が起きてんだろう？
What's going on?
現状 考えられるのは―
Right now, what comes to mind is
「電話レンジ（仮）(かっこかり)」の
電磁波の影響だな
the EM wave effect from the Phone Microwave. (name subject to change)
Why think that?
（橋田）ソースは？
It's my intuition as a mad scientist.
マッドサイエンティストの勘だ
So, no reason.
（橋田）根拠なしっと
おっしゃ 接続 終わった
Okay, it's all set.
Okay, then let's use this.
よし　では これを使おう
Property of Mayushii
Aren't these Mayushii's?
（橋田）これ まゆ氏のじゃ？
Don't worry.
（岡部）安心しろ
まゆりから提供された研究費で―
I bought them with research funds Mayuri donated to the lab.
俺が買った物だ
（橋田）だから
それをまゆ氏のって言わね？
Doesn't that make them hers—
Now, let's toss the whole thing in and see what happens.
さあ 房ごと放り込んで
変化を確かめるのだ
Wouldn't one work? Hurr.
（橋田）１本でいいだろ 常考(じょうこう)
えっ… あっ
それで「電話レンジ（仮）」の
真の力を確かめられるのか？
Can we really discover the Phone Microwave's (name subject to change)
true power that way?
That (name subject to change) is annoying.
（橋田）その“（仮）(かっこかり)”って
めんどいから いいかげん取るべき
We should take it off already.
（岡部）むんっ
実験にカネをケチるようでは―
If we're stingy with experimental funding,
世界の支配構造を
変えることはできんぞ
we can't change the world's ruling structure!
You're the only one who wants to, you know?
変えたいのはオカリンだけだって
Really?
そうなのか？
Yeah, of course.
そりゃ そうっしょ
（電子レンジのベル）
（岡部）うん？
（橋田）はい 終了
Okay, done.
うん？
（橋田）おおっ！
（岡部）どうした？
What's wrong?
It's gone...
（橋田）消えてる バナナが
The banana's gone!
ああっ バカな！
Impossible!
あっ…
It's me.
俺だ　緊急要請 ６６６号
クーリングオフを発動させろ！
Emergency Order 666.
Initiate the cool-off!
政府の承認？
そんなことを言ってる場合では…
Government approval?
No time for that!
Talking to yourself... Fail!
（橋田）自演乙(おつ)！
Shut up!
うるさい！ どこに隠した？
Where'd you hide it?
なっ 隠したのはオカリンだろう？
Aren't you the one who hid it, Okarin?
なっ…
I see... I get it!
そうか 分かったぞ
This must be some kind of teleporter microwave!
これは もしや
テレポート可能な電子レンジ！
Wh-What?
（橋田）なっ なんだって？
That's crazy.
…って そんな無茶な
（岡部）では どう説明する？
Then how do you explain this?
We took the banana from the bunch, put it into the microwave, and—
房から ちぎり
レンジに入れたはずのバナナを…
（橋田）あっ！
（岡部）おっ！
（岡部）ゲル… バナ…
Gel-bana...
（橋田）…で でもさ
房に完全に つながってねえ？
But it's completely connected to the rest of the bunch...
ううっ 確かに さっき
１本ちぎったよな？
We definitely removed one, didn't we?
ああ た 多分
I think so...
これは やはりテレポート
It's really a teleporter?
Is that what it is?
（橋田）
そういうことになるん？
You're conducting an interesting experiment.
（紅莉栖）
興味深い実験してるんですね
Okabe Rintarou.
岡部倫太郎
No, Mr. Hououin Kyouma, wasn't it?
いえ 鳳凰院凶真さんでしたっけ？
（岡部）あっ 牧瀬… 紅莉栖！
Makise... Kurisu?
～